<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tryton | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/categories/tryton/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-19T13:02:40+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtualenv Setup for Tryton]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2014/10/16/virtualenv-setup-for-tryton/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-16T22:31:26+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2014/10/16/virtualenv-setup-for-tryton</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this post, we shall learn how to setup a virtualenv for Tryton. Any new developer
who wishes to develop on Tryton needs to know a few basic things.</p>

<p>Tryton is not for the faint-hearted. A new person can possibly take a long time to get adjusted
to the workflow.</p>

<ul>
<li>Have pip/setuptools ready. Use your package manager to get pip (apt, pacman, emerge
etc).</li>
<li>Install virtualenvwrapper. It is essential for any serious Python developer.
Follow the steps given in the virtualenvwrapper <a href="http://virtualenvwrapper.readthedocs.org/en/latest/install.html">docs</a>
to setup everything - thing such as the <code>WORKON_HOME</code> variable.</li>
<li><p>Now, before you make a virtualenv, make absolutely sure that you have a minimal
set of site packages. Site packages are those Python packages that have been
installed system-wide. Here is a list of packages that I have (via <code>pip freeze</code>) -:</p>

<pre><code class="[bash] [global pip freeze]">CDApplet==1.0
CDBashApplet==1.0
Cython==0.20.1post0
apt-xapian-index==0.45
arandr==0.1.7.1
argparse==1.2.1
chardet==2.0.1
colorama==0.2.5
defer==1.0.6
gyp==0.1
html5lib==0.999
mercurial==2.8.2
psutil==1.2.1
pycups==1.9.66
pycurl==7.19.3
pygobject==3.12.0
pysmbc==1.0.14.1
pysqlite==2.6.3
python-apt==0.9.3.5
python-debian==0.1.21-nmu2ubuntu2
python-sql==0.3
pyxdg==0.25
requests==2.2.1
six==1.8.0
stevedore==1.0.0
urllib3==1.7.1
virtualenv==1.11.6
virtualenv-clone==0.2.5
virtualenvwrapper==4.3.1
wsgiref==0.1.2
</code></pre></li>
<li>One particular package that you will find to give you headaches during the installation
is <code>pygtk</code>. This package cannot be installed via pip. Why? Because screw you, that&rsquo;s why.
Now you have two options.

<ul>
<li>Follow the steps given <a href="https://gist.github.com/ches/1094799">here</a> to install <code>pygtk</code>
inside a virtualenv. However, you will find that doing this over and over again would
be tedious.</li>
<li>What about the package that has been installed system-wide? Could we possibly use it?
Well, it turns out we can! The next step details on this method.<br/>
PS: If you don&rsquo;t have it installed system-wide, do it bruh. Use your favorite package manager,
I&rsquo;m not judgin&#8217;.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>If you listened to me two steps ago and didn&rsquo;t fall asleep - the reason I said that
one must keep a minimal set of site packages is because these shall be incorporated
into the virtualenv. These are the absolute bare-minimum requirements that every
virtualenv will get. Now issue the following command in your terminal, in whichever
directory you&rsquo;ve readied for this purpose -:</p>

<pre><code class="[bash] [virtualenv]">mkproject --system-site-packages myenv
</code></pre>

<p>Substitute myenv with any name you wish. And voila, you have your newly commissioned
virtualenv.</p></li>
<li>What does this have to do with <code>pygtk</code>, you ask? Well, since it was system-wide,
it gets incorporated into your virtualenv and you don&rsquo;t have to bother about it.</li>
</ul>


<p>And that&rsquo;s that folks! In the next post, we shall set up Postgres as Tryton uses
Postgres databases. Following that, we shall learn how to actually install Tryton,
both the client and the server.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
