<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Electronics | Pritish Chakraborty]]></title>
  <link href="http://PritishC.github.io/blog/categories/electronics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PritishC.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-03T12:40:07+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://PritishC.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pritish Chakraborty]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Ode to Nokia]]></title>
    <link href="http://PritishC.github.io/blog/2014/10/22/an-ode-to-nokia/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-22T10:11:23+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://PritishC.github.io/blog/2014/10/22/an-ode-to-nokia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[So the time has finally come, ladies and gentlemen. Microsoft has decided to 
[do away with](http://www.theverge.com/2014/10/21/7026427/microsoft-lumia-nokia-brand-replacement) the Nokia brand altogether.

<!--more-->

While Nokia will still operate as a separate business, it will focus on mapping
and network infrastructure.

I have used both a Nokia smartphone and a regular phone (dumbphone). The defining
features of Nokia&#8217;s phones (before MS came along) had always been sturdiness and
long battery life - both of which I have experienced. I spent four and a half
years with a [Nokia N900](http://www.gsmarena.com/nokia_n900-2917.php), so it 
has special memories for me.

When it was released, N900 was all the hype. Unfortunately, as bug after bug was
discovered, and many of them remained unfixed, it could not live up to the hype.
Still, it was a pretty damn good phone and I still have it - I do not intend to
sell it. Infact, I highly doubt anyone besides Linux lovers, security researchers
and the odd enthusiast would even want it.

Sporting 32 gigs of internal memory and a 5MP camera with Carl Zeiss lens, I can&#8217;t
say I didn&#8217;t have a good time with it. It wasn&#8217;t exactly an iPhone killer, but
it is good at what it&#8217;s supposed to do. Unfortunately, it never really kicked off
with a proper ecosystem of its own. It is also the only phone I have seen that
supports a terminal emulator out of the box - that means a lot for geeks like me.

The N900 is still fighting to stay relevant. The [NeoN900](http://neo900.org/) project
is definitely one to follow - interesting things are in the pipeline. For geeks
who prefer touch-and-type like me, this could be what we&#8217;re looking for. I currently
use a Sony Xperia ZR, which is pretty damn good in its own right, but it&#8217;s not
a geek&#8217;s dream smartphone. I urge you to donate to the NeoN900 project, because
it&#8217;s out of projects like these that the next big thing comes from.

Another area where the N900 still shines is in information security. [NeoPwn](www.neopwn.com)
is a suite of mobile pentetration testing tools that can be installed on the N900.
I have not tried them yet - if I do in future, I will definitely post about it!
So far, all I have done is use [aircrack-ng](www.aircrack-ng.org) to _obtain_
(ahem) a neighbour&#8217;s WiFi password - they were still using the WEP form of encryption -
as an experiment with Kali Linux. But that is for another day, another post.

Thanks for all the good (and shitty) times, Nokia.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
