<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Microsoft | Pritish Chakraborty]]></title>
  <link href="http://PritishC.github.io/blog/categories/microsoft/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PritishC.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-11-11T19:59:43+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://PritishC.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pritish Chakraborty]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[WIP] eBay India: A Cautionary Tale of Pain &amp; Frustration]]></title>
    <link href="http://PritishC.github.io/blog/2017/11/11/ebay-india-a-cautionary-tale-of-pain-and-frustration/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-11T14:13:04+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://PritishC.github.io/blog/2017/11/11/ebay-india-a-cautionary-tale-of-pain-and-frustration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[As Flipkart attempts to breathe new life into the dead and decrepit Indian arm of eBay with its
"Reboxed" sale and other promotions, I provide you with a cautionary tale which will keep
online shoppers awake at night (long post ahead).

<!--more-->

I&#8217;m sure eBay users have been bombarded with &#8220;#REBOXED: *Try toh karke dekho*!&#8221; e-mails at some point. I&#8217;m
not sure how well eBay are doing after their recent acquisition by Flipkart, but they&#8217;re alive still.
The irony of them promoting refurbished items is what prompted me to write this post - almost eight months
after I bought a (poorly) refurbished Xbox One from a seller on eBay, only to find that it was dead-on-arrival. What
followed was months of frustration and back-and-forth with eBay India&#8217;s PaisaPay Guarantee team and
Microsoft support. Amazon and Flipkart users (especially the former - their service is truly exceptional) are
used to being coddled by their customer support teams. If you are expecting even 30% of the same, if not the exact
same, from eBay India, **this post will make you change your mind**.

Having pooled in for a close friend&#8217;s Xbox One purchase, I was quite keen to acquire my own so that we could
co-op together on Xbox Live. My friend is quite good at finding discounted electronics online, and his
recommendations usually stand the test of time. From a bunch of links that he gave, I stumbled upon this
[product listing](http://www.ebay.in/itm/182450551861?_trksid=p2060353.m2749.l2649&ssPageName=STRK%3AMEBIDX%3AIT) (it might not be available now, but I will provide screenshots below).

Here is a rough timeline of the events that transpired -:

**April 4**: I purchased the device. The seller shipped it in 4 days, which was quick, but I had no idea
what was coming. The device was supposed to have a 6-month Microsoft warranty, and I&#8217;d paid 18k for it.
The market price at the time was 26k or so, so it seemed like a great deal.

**April 8**: The device wouldn&#8217;t boot fully and get past the Xbox start animation. This is popularly known as the
&#8220;Green Screen of Death&#8221;. I had tried Microsoft&#8217;s device reset technique to no avail. I then filed an eBay
guarantee claim on their portal. Below is a recording of the product listing that I took (view in fullscreen mode).

<video width='700' height='400' preload='none' controls poster='https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/MnElzFvLONkv3jxJwNJW7aSOa81_sjwvbLAMIynmeVjmLgrvYLhZtSA2Vpv94OFWo6ak8I37N_KW94E=w853-h480-n-k-rw'><source src='https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=0BwmnpLMd0XH9Y1IycVFpdGdDdzQ' ></video>

**April 9**: I received a call from eBay&#8217;s claims team. The guy was not in the *least bit* interested in
resolving my issue. He kept parroting the &#8220;fact&#8221; that the device **was under warranty, and that I should go
to the manufacturer and get the device replaced**. He repeatedly said that they would close the claim.
It took me a few seconds to process what the *hell* was going on, but once I got my bearings, I shot back
that **if the seller would&#8217;ve specified on their listing that the device was to be non-functional/dead,
I would&#8217;ve not purchased it in the first place**.

This seemed to confuse the claims guy, and he put me on hold for 10 more minutes. He then reiterated that
**eBay&#8217;s policy on refurbished items under &#8220;warranty&#8221; prevents them from doing anything about it**, but said
that he would not close my claim as per my request. Bear in mind that all this happened during the time I was
getting into my car to head to office. The guy wasted a good 20-25 minutes of my time heckling me with
&#8220;close claim huehuehuehu&#8221; and left just as unceremoniously. After this incident, my claim would go into a
black hole for 10 days.

**April 15**: I emailed eBay customer support about my claim because they were just dilly-dallying at this point,
probably hoping that I would give up and close it myself. I wasn&#8217;t going to do such a thing.

**April 18**: I received a customer support reply stating that they were still investigating my case and that I
should be patient. In the meanwhile, they kept asking me to **upload higher quality images of the device on their
claims portal**. I offered to give them videos that I&#8217;d recorded of the device failing to boot, but they did not
acknowledge it. **There was no option to upload videos on their portal, almost as if it was designed to frustrate
the customer**. I sent these videos in emails to their customer service, but they ignored them each time.

<video width='700' height='400' preload='none' controls poster=''><source src='https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DxuPCr_Ox1j28YfVP0CHgK3AIy0V_pwr3Q' ></video>

**April 25**: On my very first call with eBay (claims team, which is different from their support team, as I would
come to realize later), I had also requested followup with a seniorperson, but they had refused to oblige, stating
that they would say the same thing. On 25th, I received a call from eBay support while I was driving back home, so
I told them that I could not talk at the moment. They continued to send automated emails about uploading higher quality
images on my claim page.

**April 26**: I emailed them and asked them to call at a specific time in the evening. No luck.

**April 27**: Their claims team called me up and told me **that my claim was going to be rejected**. I asked to talk
to a seniorperson but once again, they told me that the senior would say the same thing. I argued a lot but it led
to a dead end. That night, I finally decided to check Microsoft&#8217;s Xbox portal and found, to my ironic amusement,
**that the device was not even under warranty**. After all of eBay&#8217;s stonewalling, I learned that I could not even
take the device to a Microsoft service center.

I tried emailing customer support about this several times on the Friday of that week, with proof of warranty having
expired in 2016, but I got the same reply from multiple support team executives - **that I would need to acquire a
dead-on-arrival letter from a Microsoft service center**, with the appraiser&#8217;s contact details and address. I was going
to find out that no one &#8220;goes&#8221; to a Microsoft service center - we&#8217;re meant to request pickup-and-drop if the machine is
under warranty. eBay was hell-bent on making this impossible for me, and I just wouldn&#8217;t take the hint.

**April 29-30**: I called up eBay customer service, argued with the service executive and got through to a senior executive.
I told this executive (Ms. Baninder, posted at eBay&#8217;s Gujarat center) the steps I took to confirm that my device was indeed
not under warranty, and **she repeated the steps exactly as I told her to**. She then informed me that she would be forwarding
this proof of expiry to the claims team internally, and that they would contact me in 48 hours. This cost me my Saturday evening.

<span class='caption-wrapper'><img class='caption' src='/images/xbox/xbox_serial.JPG' width='' height='' title='The serial number from the machine'><span class='caption-text'>The serial number from the machine</span></span>

<span class='caption-wrapper'><img class='caption' src='/images/xbox/xbox_warranty.png' width='' height='' title='Proof of expiry'><span class='caption-text'>Proof of expiry</span></span>

<span class='caption-wrapper'><img class='caption' src='/images/xbox/xbox_warranty_full.png' width='' height='' title='Full view of proof of expiry'><span class='caption-text'>Full view of proof of expiry</span></span>

**May 1**: The claims team called me back and, as you might have guessed by now, stonewalled even further. They asked
**for a Dead-On-Arrival/service center authorization letter**, and that they would not reopen my claim without it. They were
adamant about this, throwing around the &#8220;policy&#8221; word and pretending to be helpless about it. An hour of my office work-time
went to waste. The support team wasn&#8217;t very supportive either: they kept treating the matter as if they had thoroughly
investigated it and claimed that the device was under &#8220;manufacturer warranty&#8221;, even after I&#8217;d shown them that it was not.
The implication of all this was that I was lying to them, which was insulting to put it very mildly.

I decided to contact Microsoft support in parallel. They informed me that Microsoft does not provide DOA letters and you
can&#8217;t go to a service center (i.e., they aren&#8217;t customer-facing). They construed a screenshot of their Xbox portal showing
proof of expiry as legal evidence. I also got the support executive to email me from a Microsoft-verified address that the
device was indeed expired. I forwarded this to eBay, but at this juncture, I knew it was pointless.

<img src="/images/xbox/microsoft/1.png">

<img src="/images/xbox/microsoft/2.png">

<img src="/images/xbox/microsoft/3.png">

**May 2**: I had my final call with eBay support. I was told that my case could be forwarded back to the claims team, but
that they would only reject it without this mythical DOA letter. I provided all the information and evidence to them one
last time, but their reply had the familiar phrases - &#8220;policy&#8221;, &#8220;DOA&#8221;, &#8220;service center&#8221;, &#8220;can&#8217;t do anything&#8221;.

After this, on the advice of my friend (last ditch effort), I contacted the seller on eBay with all the information,
as well as a mild threat that I would take the matter to court. They never responded, and what was even funnier was that
there were **several other people who complained about this seller on eBay&#8217;s product ratings page for various product listings**.
Some of them had a similar complaint to mine - that the product was dysfunctional and not under warranty as claimed by the seller.
I couldn&#8217;t fathom how this guy continued to sell on eBay, but then I figured that if eBay Guarantee was full of such *horseshit*,
of course the guy would get away with it.

<span class='caption-wrapper'><img class='caption' src='/images/xbox/xbox_seller_feedback.png' width='' height='' title='I'm not surprised one bit'><span class='caption-text'>I&#8217;m not surprised one bit</span></span>

<div id="discourse-comments"></div>
<script type="text/javascript">
  var discourseUrl = "",
      discourseEmbedUrl = "http://PritishC.github.io/blog/2017/11/11/ebay-india-a-cautionary-tale-of-pain-and-frustration/";

  (function() {
    var d = document.createElement('script'); d.type = 'text/javascript'; d.async = true;
      d.src = discourseUrl + 'javascripts/embed.js';
    (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(d);
  })();
</script>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
